http://www.library.vcu.edu/about/guidelines/copyright-privacy/

Home / About Us / Guidelines / Copyright and Privacy
VCU Libraries is online and in person. VCU Libraries COVID-19 response
Tompkins-McCaw Library and Cabell Library are open. Find out what to expect when you visit. FAQ
Copyright and Privacy
Copyright help
VCU Libraries offers help understanding copyright as part of our commitment to educate the VCU community about copyright, fair use, intellectual property, and related issues affecting teaching, research and scholarship.
VCU Libraries copyright
All content created by the VCU Libraries faculty and staff on the VCU Libraries website is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0) License. Other materials found on this website, such as photographs, trademarks, logos, etc., may be copyrighted by their sources or may be in the public domain. If you have questions, Ask Us.
The Commons on Flickr
Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Libraries participates in The Commons on Flickr to further its educational mission and to increase public access to its collections of images.
The photos we have posted in our collection are to be used for educational, research or personal purposes. High-resolution files of these images are available upon request. Please visit our Flickr Commons page to learn more about the VCU Libraries' Flickr Commons project.
Privacy
Virginia Commonwealth University and VCU Libraries are strongly committed to maintaining the privacy of those individuals who share confidential personal information and other highly sensitive information with us. In addition to VCU's privacy statement, VCU Libraries is committed to protecting the privacy of our Website visitors.
Personal information collected
Data collected from forms
When you choose to provide personal information to us to conduct an online transaction, we use it only for the purpose of conducting the specific online transaction that you requested. For each online transaction, we require only the minimum amount of personal information required to process your request. Examples of personal information that may be required to process an online transaction include:
name
academic status (faculty, graduate, etc)
email address
telephone number
postal address
VCUCard number
credit card number
We do not give, share, sell or transfer any personal information you enter in a form to a third party unless required to do so by law. If you do not want any personal information collected, please do not submit it to us; however, without this information we will be unable to process your online transaction. If you want to review or correct personal information you previously submitted, please Ask Us.
Data collected from social media
In coordination with VCU, our Facebook pages use a data aggregator, EverTrue, to collect publicly available data, such as profile names, comments and other social interaction information. This information is cross-referenced with other personal data that has been gathered with your informed consent, such as mailing lists. You can opt out of our use of your information by sending an email to VCU Development and Alumni Relations.
Non-Personal information collected
We collect non-personal information from every visitor to the VCU Libraries Website. For example, to track the number of computers used to visit our site and to identify our most popular pages we collect the Internet Protocol address - a series of distinct numbers that identify your computer. Other examples of this type of information include the:
browser type and version and the operating system you are using,
domain name of the Website or internet service provider and referral site from which you linked to our site
geographical location of the network used for accessing the VCU Libraries Website, and
time and date of access.
We use this non-personal information primarily in a statistical summary type format to assess site content and server performance.
Third-party services
VCU and VCU Libraries use Google Analytics to analyze web visitor statistics and improve web services for site users. These third-party services use a persistent cookie to gather non-personally identifiable information such as network location; hostname; web pages requested; referring web page; browser used; screen resolution; and date and time.
You may opt out of Google Analytics by turning off cookies in your browser preferences or installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.
Use of cookies
We use non-persistent cookies to deliver to you a number of services, and discard the cookies as soon as you close your web browser.
In addition, some of the databases to which the VCU Libraries subscribes use cookies to save the information that you input while progressing through a search. If your browser is not configured to "accept" cookies, you will still be able to access the information on our Website, but you may not be able to perform online searches in all of our databases.
Security
The VCU Libraries site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control.
Comments or review
If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of the VCU Libraries Website or if you choose to review or correct any of your personal information you previously submitted, please contact us.
Need help?
